うっ　ふわぁ～。
あっ！　わっ！？　うわっ！
Wha—?!
何だ　これは！？
What is this?!
How terrible!
ひでぇな　おい！
誰が　やったんだ！？
Who did this?!
（ナルト）ヒヒヒヒ！
Naruto Uzumaki,
at your service!
うずまきナルト　参上！
I'm going to become the Hokage,
no matter what!
俺は　必ず火影になるってばよ！
ふざけんな！
コラ！
Hey!
戻ってこいよ！
おい！
Come back!
You won't get away with this!
待て！
コラ！
クソッ！　またアイツか！
Damn it!
It was him again!
He's made a big mess.
まったく…　メチャクチャにしやがって。
文句言おうにも
アイツには文句言う親もいねえし。
Even if we want to file a complaint,
he doesn't have any parents
we can complain to!
どうすんのよ。
誰が　これ弁償してくれるのさ。
What'll we do?
Who's going to pay for all this?
ニッ　ヘヘヘ！　ヘヘヘのヘ！
Who do we complain to?
文句言おうにも　ねぇ…。
ああ　例のアイツか！
Was it him again?
Yes, the boy whose name is taboo.
ええ　例の禁句の子。
迷惑だ。
ホントよね。
What a nuisance.
– He's so unpleasant.
– I'll say.
He's such a pain.
面倒くせぇな。
いってきます！
I'm leaving!
忘れ物よ！
You forgot something!
Oops! What did you make us
for lunch?
いっけねぇ！　今日のおかず何？
卵焼き入ってる？
Did you put in omelets?
ああ　いっぱい入れといたよ。
Yes, I put in lots.
– Yes!
（２人）やった～！
Be careful now!
気をつけて行っといで！
（２人）は～い！
– Okay!
邪魔するぞ。
Can I come in?
今月の生活費じゃ。
ムダ遣いするでないぞ。
This is for this month's living expenses.
Spend it wisely now.
なぁ…。
うん？
Hey...
Hmm?
なんで俺には　父ちゃんと
母ちゃんが　いないんだ？
Why don't I have a mom and dad?
う～む　前にも話さんかったかな。
もう　ずいぶん前になる…。
Didn't I tell you before?
Although it was
quite some time ago...
そんな話が聞きたいんじゃない！
That's not what I want to hear!
里が九尾のバケ狐に
襲われたって話だろ？
You're talking about
when that beast called
the Nine Tailed Fox Spirit
ran amuck, right?
And that a lot of people
in the village were killed,
そのとき　たくさんの
里の人が犠牲になって→
俺の父ちゃんと母ちゃんも…。
including my mom and dad...
けど　俺が聞きてぇのは
そんな話じゃねえんだ。
Well, that's not
what I'm asking about!
I just want to know...
俺が聞きてぇのは　俺の→
俺の父ちゃんと母ちゃんは
誰なんだ？
Who were my parents?
そんで　どんな人だったんだ？
What kind of people were they?
それを聞いても　せんないこと。
There's no use asking about that.
It won't bring the dead back.
亡くなった者が
よみがえることはない。
it's infinite, it's infinite, it's infinite, rock assault
eien desu eien desu eien desu totsugeki rock
I was asleep all this time, I kept quiet all this time
zutto nemutteta zutto damatteta
hey, it's calling us, hey, let's go
ooi yonde iru ooi itte mi yo
I can see something far away
tooku ni nanika ga mieru
something more important now than studying
benkyou yori mo ima taisetsu na mono
hey, it's calling us, hey, let's go
ooi yonde iru ooi itte mi yo
I think we can find it
mitsukarisou nanda
it's infinite, it's infinite, it's infinite, rock assault
eien desu eien desu eien desu totsugeki rock
see, you can overtake the future
mirai wa hora oinuite
this ship can really fly through the sky
hontou wa sora toberu fune
Meeting
10th Anniversary 4-Episode Special
（イルカ）さ～て　次の授業は
自己紹介のかわりに→
Now then,
for the next lesson.
Instead of just
introducing yourselves,
みんなの忍術の
実力を見せてもらうぞ。
I want you to demonstrate
your ninjutsu skills.
（みんな）えぇ～。
So, we'll try a basic jutsu.
The Clone Jutsu.
（イルカ）そうだな
基本的な術を見せてもらおうか。
分身の術だ。
First up is Sasuke Uchiha.
まずは…　うちはサスケ　やってみろ。
Try it out.
（いの）うちは　って
あの　うちは一族？
Uchiha? As in the Uchiha Clan?
Yes, he's an elite among the elites.
（サクラ）えぇ！　エリート中のエリートよ。
（みんな）キャーッ！
（サスケ）フン！
You always act so smug
and I can't stand it!
キサマ！　いつも　すかしやがって
気に入らねえんだよ！！
Brag, after you prove it.
やってから
でかい態度　とれってんだ！
I intend to.
そのつもりだが。
いつの間に！？
When did you—?!
うん　みごとだ。
Well done.
（みんな）ホニャニャニャ…。
ホニャニャニャって…。
フン！　こんな術　本体を攻めりゃ…。
With this jutsu,
if you attack the real one—!
あっ！
うん　ぶざまだ。
It's useless.
あ…　あぁ～！
– What an idiot.
– So pitiful.
Damn it!
クソ！　あんにゃろう
今日こそ　ぶっ飛ばしてやる！！
I'm gonna pulverize him today
for sure...
ってばよ！
Ya know!
（みんな）キャーッ！
クソ！　クソ！　クソ　クソ　クソ！！
Damn it! Damn it!
Damn it! Damn it! Damn it!
（みんな）キャーッ！
Oh man! Oh man!
だぁ～！　あぁ！　もう！！
Even Choji?!
チョウジにまで！
Damn it!
チクショウ！
Definitely today!
今日こそは…　今日こそは！
今日こそは！！
Definitely today!
（イルカ）次　うずまきナルト。
Next, Naruto Uzumaki. And...
そして　うちはサスケ。
キャーッ！　サスケ君！！
Sasuke Uchiha!
Sasuke!
（いの）サスケ君　頑張って！
（サクラ）サスケ君なら　きっと　ボッコボコよ！
Do your best, Sasuke!
You're totally going to win!
《クソ！　なんで　アイツばっかり…》
Damn it!
Why does he always
get the attention?
I'm not going to lose!
ぜってぇ　負けねえ！
（イルカ）始め！
Start!
すげぇ　かっけぇ！
サスケ君　すごい！
Amazing! He's so cool!
Sasuke, you're terrific!
《コイツ…　この目。
This guy...
That look in his eyes...
いつも　俺を見る　みんなの目…。
It's the same look that
everyone gives me.
いや　それよりも　もっと強ぇ。
No...
It's stronger than that.
けど…》
But...
《俺を見てねえ》
But it's not for me...
ムシャクシャする！
He pisses me off!
Hey!
コラ！
エヘヘヘヘ！
Not him again!
You rascal!
Damn it, where did he go?!
クソ！　どこ行きやがった！？
あっちだ！
Over there!
ヘヘヘ！　ざまぁ　みやがれ。
Serves you right!
ん？
I acted like the older brother
you desired...
((イタチ：お前が望むような兄を
演じ続けてきたのは→
in order to measure your vessel.
(お前の器を確かめるためだ))
♪～
≪知ってるか？　うちは一族って
みんな　殺されたらしいぜ。
Did you hear?
Everyone in the Uchiha Clan
was killed.
Yeah, I know.
I heard my dad talking about it.
あぁ　知ってる　知ってる。
父ちゃんも言ってた。
生き残ったの　アイツだけらしいぜ。
He's the only one who survived.
♪～
今日から　こいつだ！
Starting from today,
I get to wear this!
ヘヘ…　ヘヘヘヘ！
Perfect!
キマった！
よ～し　今日から下忍だぜ！
All right, I'm a genin from today!
（カカシ）そうだな…
まずは　自己紹介してもらおう。
Let's see, we'll start with
the introductions.
俺さ　俺さ　名前は　うずまきナルト。
好きなものは　カップラーメン。
I'll go! I'll go!
I'm Naruto Uzumaki!
I love instant ramen.
もっと好きなもんは→
But I love the ramen at Ichiraku
イルカ先生におごってもらった
一楽のラーメン！
that Iruka Sensei treats me to
even more!
嫌いなものは
お湯を入れてからの３分間。
And I hate having to wait
three minutes
after pouring in the hot water.
将来の夢は…　火影を超す！
My future dream is...
to surpass the Hokage!
And that's why I'm going to make
でもって　里のヤツら全員に
俺の存在を認めさせてやんだ！
everyone in the village
acknowledge me!
（カカシ）趣味は？
え？　う～ん…。
Any hobbies?
イタズラかな。
次。
Playing pranks.
Next.
名は　うちはサスケ。
My name is Sasuke Uchiha.
嫌いなものなら　たくさんあるが
好きなものは別にない。
There are lots of things I hate.
And not many things I like.
それから…　夢なんて言葉で
終わらす気はないが　野望はある。
Also, I have no intention of
saying I have a dream,
but I do have an ambition.
That is to...
ある男を必ず…。
殺すことだ。
kill a certain man one day.
（カカシ）自己紹介は　そこまでだ。
明日から　任務やるぞ。
That's it for the introductions.
We start our mission tomorrow.
はい！　どんな任務でありますか？
What kind of mission?
まずは　この４人だけで
あることをやる。
There is something just the four of us
are going to do.
What? What?
何？　何！？
サバイバル演習だ。
A survival exercise.
相手は俺だが
ただの演習じゃない。
I'll be your opponent,
but it won't just be an exercise.
この演習は
脱落率６６％以上の超難関試験だ。
This is an extremely difficult test
that has a 66% failure rate.
サスケく～ん！　一緒に帰りましょう。
Sasuke, let's walk home together!
断る。　やっと下忍になったのに
ここで落とされてたまるか。
No thanks.
I'm finally a genin and
I have no intention
on getting dropped.
俺は一人で修業する。
I'm going to train alone.
そうだよね…。
I guess you're right.
ったく…　スカしやがって。
Putting on airs!
これでよし！
All right!
サスケが修業すんなら
俺もやらなきゃな。
If Sasuke's going to train,
so will I!
サスケなんかに負けてたまるかよ！
I'm not going to lose to him!
いくぜ　カカシティーチャー！
Here I come, Kakashi Sensei!
でやぁ～っ！
アタタタ！
絶対に受かってやるってばよ！
I'm going to be a genin,
no matter what!
Damn it... Of all people,
I had to get stuck
《よりによって　スリーマンセルが
サクラと　あのウスラトンカチとは！》
with Sakura and that loser
in the three-man cell.
《一人でも必ず受かる！
I can pass, even by myself.
俺には目標があるんだ》
I have a goal.
Okay, the clock's been
set to 12 o'clock.
（カカシ）よ～し　１２時に　セットオーケー。
ここに　鈴が２つある。
There are two bells here.
これを俺から
昼までに奪い取ることが課題だ。
Your task is to take these bells away
from me by noon.
奪えなかったヤツは　昼飯抜き。
The one who fails to take
a bell gets no lunch.
And failing the exercise means
failing the mission.
で　任務失敗ってことで失格だ。
つまり　この中で最低でも１人は→
In other words, at the very least,
one of you will be returning
to the Academy.
アカデミーへ
戻ってもらうことになるわけだ。
用意…。
Ready...
スタート！
Start!
I'm just going to go for it,
like I always do!
いざ！　尋常に勝負！！
《あの　ウスラトンカチ…》
That loser.
MAKE-OUT PARADISE
ボッコボコにしてやる！
I'm gonna pulverize him!
だ～っ！！
ヒイーッ！
Damn it!
《チクショウ…
こんな…　こんなはずじゃ…》
This... This wasn't supposed to...
ぐはっ！
ありっ？
うわ～っ！
あ～っ！
♪～
火遁　豪火球の術！
Fire Style: Fireball Jutsu!
ヘヘヘヘヘ…。
バカ正直に
鈴なんか取らなくっても→
Why should I steal a stupid bell?
今　隠れて食っちまえばいいのだ。
I can hide and eat right now!
いただきま～す！
Thank you for the food!
Hey.
おい。
っていうのは冗談で…。
I was just joking.
遅い。
Too late!
３人で来れば　鈴を取れたかもな。
If you three had worked together,
you might have gotten the bell.
これは　わざと仲間割れするように
仕組んだ試験だ。
This exercise was devised
to break up the team
and see what you would do.
お前ら　最後に
もう一度だけ　チャンスをやる。
Well, guys, I'm going to give
you one more chance.
だが　昼からは
もっと過酷な鈴取り合戦だ。
However, the afternoon
scramble for the bells
will be much more difficult.
挑戦したいヤツだけ　弁当を食え。
If you accept the challenge,
eat your lunch.
ただし　ナルトには食わせるな。
えっ？
However, don't let Naruto eat.
Huh?
ルールを破って
一人　昼飯　食おうとした罰だ。
That's your punishment for
breaking the rule
and attempting to eat lunch alone.
もし　食わせたりしたら→
If you give Naruto any food,
ソイツを　その時点で試験失格にする。
you will be immediately
disqualified.
ここでは　俺がルールだ。
I am the law here.
わかったな？
Understand?
へっ！　俺ってば　別に
飯なんか食わなくったって平気…。
Like I care if I don't get to eat.
I don't need any food!
《カカシから鈴を奪う。
To steal a bell from Kakashi...
悔しいが
確かに　俺一人の力では無理だ。
As much as I hate to admit it,
I can't do it alone.
どうする？
What should I do...?
３人の力を　ひとつに…》
Combine the strength
of three into one...
ほらよ。
ちょっとサスケ君。
Here...
H-Hey Sasuke! Didn't you hear
what Sensei said?!
さっき先生が…。
大丈夫だ。
It's all right. He's not around.
今　アイツの気配はない。
昼からは３人で鈴を取りに行く。
The three of us will go and
get the bell this afternoon.
足手まといになられちゃ
こっちが困るからな。
It will be trouble
if he hinders me, so...
サクラちゃん。
Sakura!
サンキューだってばよ。
Thank you!
だぁ～！
You pass.
合格。
フッ。
忍の世界でルールや掟を破るヤツは
クズ呼ばわりされる。
In the ninja world,
those who break the rules are scum.
けどな　仲間を大切にしないヤツは
それ以上のクズだ。
But those who abandon their friends,
are worse than scum.
これにて　練習終わり。
That ends the survival exercise.
全員集合！
You all pass.
はいはい　写真撮るから
みんなちゃんとして。
Okay, picture time. Look sharp!
何で俺がこんなスカシ野郎と一緒に
写んなきゃいけねえんだってばよ。
Why do I have to be in
the same picture as this guy?!
こっちのセリフだ。　ウスラトンカチ。
That's what I'd like to know,
you loser!
何だと！
まぁまぁ。
Say that again!
Come on, guys.
This is a tradition.
そうは言ってもこれ決まりだから。
ね。
第７班は明日から任務開始だ。
Team 7 will start its mission tomorrow!
何？
What?!
１匹目。
The first one!
カカシ先生！
Kakashi Sensei!
うわ～っ！
２匹目。
The second one!
《す　すげえ》
A-Amazing!
う　うわ～っ！
♪～
《カカシ先生　変わり身
使ってたのか》
Kakashi Sensei
was using a Substitution...
《俺ってば　何もできなかった。
I-I couldn't do a thing.
なのにコイツは初めての実戦なのに→
Yet he...
It's our first real combat situation...
ちっとも怖いって
思わなかったのか。
yet wasn't he scared at all?
平気な顔して
服に汚れひとつ　つけずに→
He looked like nothing
was happening,
and didn't even get
his clothes dirty...
俺のことを助けたっていうのか》
and he saved me?
よう。
Hey...
ケガはねえかよ　ビビリ君。
Are you hurt, scaredy cat?
《どうして　こんなに違う。
Why're we so different?
どうして俺のほうがいつも…。
How come I'm always the one...?
ちくしょう！》
Damn it!
♪～
《俺ってば　もう２度と
助けられるような真似はしねえ。
I'll never let myself get
into a situation
where I need to be rescued.
おじけづいたり
逃げ腰にもならねえ。
And I won't get scared
or run away.
この左手の痛みに
誓うんだってばよ》
I swear it on the pain
of this left hand!
you and I held hands tightly and a light was born
kimi to boku nigirishimeta futatsu no te no naka de
let's release it now
umareta hikari ima hanatou
the town, tinged amber by the sunset
kohaku iro no yuuyake ni somerareta
projects a sad light and shadow
machi wa kanashii hikari to kage utsushite ita
I've encountered and gotten tangled
ikutsu mono kiseki no ito
in so many miraculous threads
tsunagatte karamatte tadoritsuita yo
it all starts here and now
hajimeru no wa ima kono basho kara
it'll clear up after the rain, become that cloud
ame nochi hare ano kumo ni nare
and swim towards the present
ima wo oyoi de yuku
toss away the hesitation
sono kokoro shibaritsuketeru
that clings to your heart
tamerai furihodoite
you and I held hands
kimi to boku nigirishimeta
and deep inside
futatsu no te no naka de
is the eternal proof of you
kieru koto nai kimi no akashi
with our liberated hands
jiyuu na sono ryoute de
let's start again, from here
koko kara mata hajimeyou
Next Episode
[スピーカ]皆様　お変わりございませんか？
If you don't want to owe me anything,
you should just get stronger than me, you loser.
美空ひばりです。
では最後まで　ごゆっくり→
Damn it! I'll catch up to you and surpass you in strength!
お楽しみください。
（宮本）『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！　にっぽんの歌』。
Next on Naruto Shippuden: "Rivals"
10th Anniversary 4-Episode Special
Rivals
２時間スペシャル。
When did he get this strong?
（松丸）今回は　ご覧の豪華歌手の
皆さんによる→
Tune in again!